[
 {
   "ref": "ale0002",
   "topic": "Alertness",
   "question": "Whats should you do before making a U-turn?",
   "tans": "look over your shoulder for a final check",
   "ans1": "choose a higher gear",
   "ans2": "check road marking to make sure U-turns are permitted",
   "ans3": "give an arm signal as well as using your indicators",
   "hint": "",
   "diagram": false
 },
 {
   "ref": "ale0003",
   "topic": "Alertness",
   "question": "What should you do as you approach this bridge?",
   "tans": "slow down",
   "ans1": "change gear",
   "ans2": "keep to 30 mph",
   "ans3": "move to the right",
   "hint": "",
   "diagram": true
 },
 {
   "ref": "ale0004",
   "topic": "Alertness",
   "question": "Where should you avoid overtaking",
   "tans": "before a dip in the road",
   "ans1": "on a 30 mph road",
   "ans2": "in a one-way street",
   "ans3": "just after a bend",
   "hint": "",
   "diagram": false
 },
 {
   "ref": "ale0005",
   "topic": "Alertness",
   "question": "What does this curved arrow marking mean?",
   "tans": "overtaking traffic should keep to the left",
   "ans1": "the road has a camber to the left",
   "ans2": "lorries should take the next road on the left to avoid a weight limit",
   "ans3": "road ahead bends to left",
   "hint": "",
   "diagram": true
 },
 {
   "ref": "ale0006",
   "topic": "Alertness",
   "question": "What should you do if your phone rings while driving?",
   "tans": "wait to answer it until you have stopped in a safe place",
   "ans1": "answer it immediately",
   "ans2": "stop where you are",
   "ans3": "pull up on the nearest curb",
   "hint": "",
   "diagram": false
 },
 {
   "ref": "ale0007",
   "topic": "Alertness",
   "question": "What are these yellow lines painted across the road for?",
   "tans": "to help make you aware of your speed",
   "ans1": "help you choose the correct lane",
   "ans2": "help keep the correct seperation distance",
   "ans3": "tell you the distance to the roundabout",
   "hint": "",
   "diagram": true
 },
 {
   "ref": "ale0008",
   "topic": "Alertness",
   "question": "What should you do when you're approaching traffic lights that have been green for a while?",
   "tans": "be ready to stop",
   "ans1": "accelerate hard",
   "ans2": "maintain your speed",
   "ans3": "brake hard",
   "hint": "",
   "diagram": false
 },
 {
   "ref": "ale0009",
   "topic": "Alertness",
   "question": "What should you do before slowing down or stopping your vehicle?",
   "tans": "use the mirrors",
   "ans1": "sound the horn",
   "ans2": "select a higher gear",
   "ans3": "flash the headlights",
   "hint": "",
   "diagram": false
 },
 {
   "ref": "ale0010",
   "topic": "Alertness",
   "question": "You're following a large vehicle. Why should you stay a safe distance behind it?",
   "tans": "you'll give the driver a chance to see you in their mirrors",
   "ans1": "you'll keep out the wind more",
   "ans2": "you'll help the large vehicle stop easier",
   "ans3": "you'll be able to corner more quickly",
   "hint": "",
   "diagram": false
 },
 {
   "ref": "ale0011",
   "topic": "Alertness",
   "question": "Why should you use your mirrors when you see a hazard ahead?",
   "tans": "to assess how your actions will affect drivers behind you",
   "ans1": "you'll need to accelerate out of danger",
   "ans2": "you'll need to brake and stop sharply",
   "ans3": "to check what's happening on the road ahead",
   "hint": "",
   "diagram": false
 },
 {
   "ref": "ale0012",
   "topic": "Alertness",
   "question": "You're waiting to turn right at the end of a road. What should you do if your view is obstructed by parked vehicles?",
   "tans": "stop then move forward slowly and carefully for a clearer view",
   "ans1": "move quickly to where you can see so you only block traffic in one direction",
   "ans2": "wait for a pedestrian to let you know when it's safe",
   "ans3": "turn around and find another junction",
   "hint": "",
   "diagram": false
 },
 {
   "ref": "ale0013",
   "topic": "Alertness",
   "question": "Why can things hanging from your mirror be a hazard?",
   "tans": "your view may be obstructed",
   "ans1": "your sun visor might get tangled",
   "ans2": "your radio may be affected",
   "ans3": "your windscreen may mist up",
   "hint": "",
   "diagram": false
 },
 {
   "ref": "ale0014",
   "topic": "Alertness",
   "question": "What should you do on a long journey if you start to feel sleepy?",
   "tans": "find a safe place to stop and rest",
   "ans1": "drive faster so you finish the journey quicker",
   "ans2": "play loud music",
   "ans3": "stop and rest on the hard shoulder",
   "hint": "",
   "diagram": false
 },
 {
   "ref": "ale0015",
   "topic": "Alertness",
   "question": "Why should you switch on your headlights when it starts to get dark?",
   "tans": "so others can more easily see you",
   "ans1": "to blend in with other drivers",
   "ans2": "because the streetlights are lit",
   "ans3": "make your dials easier to see",
   "hint": "",
   "diagram": false
 },
 {
   "ref": "ale0016",
   "topic": "Alertness",
   "question": "What will most likely distract you while driving?",
   "tans": "using a mobile phone",
   "ans1": "windscreen wipers",
   "ans2": "using the demisters",
   "ans3": "using the mirrors",
   "hint": "",
   "diagram": false
 },
 {
   "ref": "ale0017",
   "topic": "Alertness",
   "question": "When may you use your mobile phone while driving?",
   "tans": "when you've safely parked",
   "ans1": "when you're receiving a call",
   "ans2": "when driving less than 30 mph",
   "ans3": "while in an automatic car",
   "hint": "",
   "diagram": false
 },
 {
   "ref": "saf0018",
   "topic": "Safety Margins",
   "question": "How do you ensure that your brakes are working properly after passing through flood water?",
   "tans": "go slow and gently apply the brakes",
   "ans1": "avoid using the brakes for a while",
   "ans2": "accelerate to a high speed for a short amount of time",
   "ans3": "stop for at least half an hour until they are dry",
   "hint": "",
   "diagram": false
 },
 {
   "ref": "saf0019",
   "topic": "Safety Margins",
   "question": "When conditions are icy what part of the vehicle should you clear of ice and snow?",
   "tans": "the windows",
   "ans1": "the bumber",
   "ans2": "the aerial",
   "ans3": "the roof",
   "hint": "",
   "diagram": false
 },
 {
   "ref": "saf0020",
   "topic": "Safety Margins",
   "question": "What light should you use when you're driving on a wet motorway and vehicles are throwing up surface spray?",
   "tans": "dipped headlights",
   "ans1": "rear fog lights",
   "ans2": "sidelights",
   "ans3": "hazard warning lights",
   "hint": "",
   "diagram": false
 },
 {
   "ref": "saf0021",
   "topic": "Safety Margins",
   "question": "You're following a vehicle on a wet road. You stay a safe distance behind it, what should you do if a car over takes into the gap you've left?",
   "tans": "drop back and regain a safe distance",
   "ans1": "try to overtake safely",
   "ans2": "flash your headlights to warn the driver",
   "ans3": "stay close to the vehicle until it moves on",
   "hint": "",
   "diagram": false
 },
 {
   "ref": "saf0022",
   "topic": "Safety Margins",
   "question": "You're following other vehicles in fog, you have your dipped headlights on, what else can you do to reduce the chances of a collision?",
   "tans": "keep a safe distance from the car in front",
   "ans1": "keep up with the faster vehicles",
   "ans2": "use main beams instead",
   "ans3": "keep close to the vehicle in front",
   "hint": "",
   "diagram": false
 },
 {
   "ref": "saf0023",
   "topic": "Safety Margins",
   "question": "You approach a sharp bend in freezing conditions what should you do?",
   "tans": "slow down gently",
   "ans1": "firmly use your footbrake",
   "ans2": "apply your parking brake",
   "ans3": "coast into the bend",
   "hint": "",
   "diagram": false
 },
 {
   "ref": "saf0024",
   "topic": "Safety Margins",
   "question": "How do you use your vehicle's engine as a brake?",
   "tans": "change to a lower gear",
   "ans1": "change to a higher gear",
   "ans2": "selecting reverse",
   "ans3": "selecting neutral",
   "hint": "",
   "diagram": false
 },
 {
   "ref": "saf0025",
   "topic": "Safety Margins",
   "question": "What can happen when you coat for a long period of time? (driving in netural)",
   "tans": "reduction in control",
   "ans1": "easier steering",
   "ans2": "improvement in control",
   "ans3": "increased fuel consumption",
   "hint": "",
   "diagram": false
 },
 {
   "ref": "saf0026",
   "topic": "Safety Margins",
   "question": "What should you do when parking your car facing down hill?",
   "tans": "engage parking brake and steer towards the kerb",
   "ans1": "engage parking brake and steer away from the kerb",
   "ans2": "park close to the bumper of another car",
   "ans3": "park with 2 wheels on the kerb",
   "hint": "",
   "diagram": false
 },
 {
   "ref": "saf0027",
   "topic": "Safety Margins",
   "question": "What would indicate you're driving on an icy road?",
   "tans": "less tyre noise",
   "ans1": "less wind noise",
   "ans2": "less transmission noise",
   "ans3": "less engine noise",
   "hint": "",
   "diagram": false
 },
 {
   "ref": "saf0028",
   "topic": "Safety Margins",
   "question": "What should you do when you approach a road hump in a built-up area?",
   "tans": "check your mirror and slow down",
   "ans1": "stop and check both pavements",
   "ans2": "wait for any pedestrians to cross",
   "ans3": "move to the left-hand side of the road",
   "hint": "",
   "diagram": true
 },
 {
   "ref": "saf0029",
   "topic": "Safety Margins",
   "question": "Driving on an open road in dry weather, what distance should you keep from the vehicle in front of you?",
   "tans": "2 second time hap",
   "ans1": "4 second time gap",
   "ans2": "one car length",
   "ans3": "2 car lengths",
   "hint": "",
   "diagram": false
 },
 {
   "ref": "saf0030",
   "topic": "Safety Margins",
   "question": "Where is your vehicle most likely to be affected by side winds?",
   "tans": "on an open stretch of road",
   "ans1": "on narrow country lanes",
   "ans2": "on busy streets in a built up area",
   "ans3": "on a long, straight road",
   "hint": "",
   "diagram": false
 },
 {
   "ref": "saf0031",
   "topic": "Safety Margins",
   "question": "Why should you keep to the left as you approach a right-hand bend?",
   "tans": "to improve you view of the road",
   "ans1": "let faster traffic overtake",
   "ans2": "be positioned safely if you skid",
   "ans3": "overcome the effect of the road's slope",
   "hint": "",
   "diagram": true
 },
 {
   "ref": "saf0032",
   "topic": "Safety Margins",
   "question": "You're travelling on the motorway, how can you lower the risk of a collision when the vehicle behind is following too closely?",
   "tans": "increase your distance to the vehicle in front",
   "ans1": "brake sharply",
   "ans2": "switch on your hazard warning lights",
   "ans3": "move onto the hard shoulder and stop",
   "hint": "",
   "diagram": false
 },
 {
   "ref": "saf0033",
   "topic": "Safety Margins",
   "question": "What requires extra care when you're driving or riding in windy conditions?",
   "tans": "passing pedal cyclists",
   "ans1": "turning into a narrow road",
   "ans2": "moving off a hill",
   "ans3": "using the brakes",
   "hint": "",
   "diagram": false
 },
 {
   "ref": "saf0034",
   "topic": "Safety Margins",
   "question": "You're about to go down a steep hill. What should you do to control the speed of your vehicle?",
   "tans": "select a low gear and use the brakes",
   "ans1": "select a low gear but don't use the brakes",
   "ans2": "select a high gear and use the brakes",
   "ans3": "select a high gear but don't use the brakes",
   "hint": "",
   "diagram": false
 },
 {
   "ref": "saf0035",
   "topic": "Safety Margins",
   "question": "What is the main cause of skidding?",
   "tans": "the driver",
   "ans1": "the weather",
   "ans2": "the vehicle",
   "ans3": "the road",
   "hint": "",
   "diagram": false
 },
 {
   "ref": "saf0036",
   "topic": "Safety Margins",
   "question": "What should you do when you're using a contraflow system?",
   "tans": "choose an appropriate lane in good time",
   "ans1": "switch lanes to make better progress",
   "ans2": "increase speed to get through the contraflow more quickly",
   "ans3": "follow other motorists closely to avoid long queues",
   "hint": "",
   "diagram": false
 },
 {
   "ref": "saf0037",
   "topic": "Safety Margins",
   "question": "You're driving along a country road, and see this sign. What should you do after dealing safely with this hazard?",
   "tans": "test your brakes",
   "ans1": "accelerate quickly",
   "ans2": "switch on your hazard warning lights",
   "ans3": "check tyre pressure",
   "hint": "",
   "diagram": true
 }
]